Register of the Vitaliĭ Leonidovich Kataev papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Soviet Military Doctrine File, 1986-1992 (Boxes 12-14)
  - Military-technical cooperation with foreign countries
    - Warsaw Treaty Organization
      - General
        - Agreement on the maximum level of conventional armaments and equipment (Bulgaria, Hungary, Poland, Romania, USSR, and Czech and Slovak Federal Republic) in connection with the agreement on conventional armaments in Europe, 1990 November 3 (Box-folder 12: 33)
      - Material on the cooperative joint enterprises of the Soviet Union and the Warsaw Treaty Organization, 1986 (Box-folder 12: 34)
      - Research materials
        - People's Republic of Bulgaria (Box-folder 12: 35)
        - People's Republic of Hungary (Box-folder 12: 36)
        - Poland (Box-folder 13: 1)
        - Czechoslovak Socialist Republic (Box-folder 13: 2)
        - German Democratic Republic (Box-folder 13: 3)
      - Information on the new military-political initiative during Mikhail Gorbachev's visit to Czechoslovakia, 1987 March 16 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Western countries
      - Agreement between the government of the Soviet Union and the government of Great Britain and Northern Ireland regarding operative notification of nuclear accident and on information exchange related to operation of nuclear plants, 1990 April 10 (Box-folder 13: 5)
      - Soviet-Canadian project on keeping outer space a weapon-free zone, 1989 August 17 (Box-folder 13: 6)
      - Resolution of the Council of Ministers of the Soviet Union on conducting negotiations and conclusion of the agreement with Canada on prevention of dangerous military activity, 1990 December (Box-folder 13: 7)
      - Information on the position of Finland on the main international issues, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - Developing (third world) countries
      - General (Box-folder 13: 9)
      - Information on Soviet military bases in "third countries" (Box-folder 13: 10)
        Includes detailed list of major military bases and objects of the United States, Great Britain, and France located outside their borders.
      - Information on relations with developing countries
        - Afghanistan, 1989 March-August (Box-folder 13: 11)
        - Argentina, 1980s (Box-folder 13: 12)
        - Brazil, 1992 December (Box-folder 13: 13)
        - India, 1989 January-October (Box-folder 13: 14)
        - Lebanon, 1980s (Box-folder 13: 15)
        - Mongolia, 1989 December (Box-folder 13: 16)
        - Romania, 1980s (Box-folder 13: 17)
        - Vietnam, 1990s (Box-folder 13: 18)
        - Zambia, 1986 December (Box-folder 13: 19)
    - Union of Independent States (ex Soviet Union Republics)
      - General, agreement, 1992 July 6 (Box-folder 13: 20)
      - Ukraine, 1992
        - Decree of the President of the Russian Federation on military-technical cooperation with foreign countries (Box-folder 13: 21)
        - Russia-Ukraine bilateral relations (Box-folder 13: 22)
        - Analytical data on military-political situation in Ukraine (Box-folder 13: 23)
        - Military and military-technical cooperation with Russia (Box-folder 13: 24)
        - Defense branches in Ukrainian industry (Box-folder 13: 25)
        - Strategic nuclear missile and other armaments in Ukraine (Box-folder 13: 26)
        - State of the Dnepropetrovsk missile center, industrial association "IUzhnoe" ("Southern") (Box-folder 13: 27)
  - Zaikov, Lev Nikolaevich (First Deputy Chief, Defense Council) material, undated (Box-folder 13: 28)
  - Arms control decision-making (the "Big Five") - meetings at the office of Lev Nikolaevich Zaikov, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 13: 29-31)
    Includes agendas and minutes of meetings.
  - Air defense material, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Defense Council of the Soviet Union documents, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Institute of the USA and Canada materials, Academy of Science of the Soviet Union
    - Study, "On the Question of Railroad Military Missile Complexes,", 1990 March 28 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Essay, A. Kokoshin, "Problems of Control of Limitation of Submarine-launched Cruise Missiles (SLCM)" (Box-folder 14: 4)
      Includes analytical report.
    - Essay, V. A. Tumanov, "Parliamentary Control over the Military Forces in Western Countries" (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Suggestions regarding some problems in military-strategic parity under the conditions of limitation of armaments (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Material regarding an agreement on reduction of strategic offensive weapons (Box-folder 14: 7)
      Includes studies with different approaches on the issue.
    - Outlook on the reduction of the US military budget, 1990 October (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Institute of Europe materials, Academy of Science of the Soviet Union (Box-folder 14: 9)
    Includes discussion of the seminar "On Military-political Issues in Relations of the Soviet Union and Federal Republic of Germany and NATO," 1990 July.
- Russian Federation and President of Russia Documents, 1989-1994 (Box 14)
  Decree, directives, orders, explanatory note, thesis, and other working materials for the President of Russia, arranged chronologically.
  - Military-political stability of development of Russia, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 14: 10)
    Includes correspondence of academician V. M. Matrosov regarding security and steadiness of development of the Russian Federation.
  - Order of the President of the Russian Federation on dissolving the organs of power of the Soviet Union, 1991 December 23 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - Explanatory note to the drafted law, "Security of the Russian Federation (RSFSR)" (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - Material for the President of Russia Boris Yeltsin on work management in the area of military construction and control over armaments (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - Additional directives to the delegation of the Russian Federation for the third session of the joint advisory board, Vienna, 1992 January 13 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - Thesis on the problem of military industry conversion, 1992 (Box-folder 14: 15)
    Includes list of specialists of the Department of Security and Defense for the ex-President of the Soviet Union.
  - Decree of the President of the Russian Federation regarding state councils on the questions of conversion, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 14: 16)
    Includes lists of appointees.
- Unification of Germany File, 1990 (Box 14)
  - General, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 17)
    Includes draft of the protocol on unification, 1990 August 7.
  - Draft agreement between the Soviet Union and Germany regarding transitional economic measures due to unification of the Federal Republic of Germany and the German Democratic Republic (Box-folder 14: 18)
  - Agreement between the government of the Soviet Union and the government of the Federal Republic of Germany regarding transitional measures (Box-folder 14: 19)
  - Draft agreement between the Soviet Union and Germany regarding terms of stay and systematic withdrawal of Soviet troops from German territory (Box-folder 14: 20)
  - Order and conditions of transfer during withdrawal of Soviet troops from German territory (Box-folder 14: 21)
  - Final draft of international legal settlement with Germany (Box-folder 14: 22)
  - Conclusion made by the Ministry of Defense of the Soviet Union (Box-folder 14: 23)
- Publications, 1986-1997 (Box 14)
  Statements, opinions, declarations, analysis, and inquiries to build public opinion against arms race, arranged chronologically.
  - Information from CPSU Central Committee regarding suggestions on SDI from the Chairman of the Union of Concerned Scientists (USA) G. Kendall (Box-folder 14: 24)
  - Invitation for a study in collaboration with the Stockholm International Institute on Research of Peace Problems, undated (Box-folder 14: 25)
  - Letter from Congressman George E. Brown to the Chairman of the Ideology Commission, Politburo of the CPSU Central Committee Vadim Medvedev regarding prevention of production of space-strike weapons, 1980s (Box-folder 14: 26)
  - Reviews of K. Bertman articles, Zeit, West Germany, 1986 May-July (Box-folder 14: 27)
    Includes material reported to Mikhail Gorbachev.
  - Critical summary of SDI in report of the American Physical Society; study of the Committee of Soviet Scientists for Peace, Against Nuclear Danger, 1987 April (Box-folder 14: 28)
  - Material on landing of a foreign airplane in downtown Moscow, 1987 June (Box-folder 14: 29)
  - Declaration of Bulgaria and Greece on the question of announcing the Balkans as a nuclear free zone, 1987 Spring (Box-folder 14: 30)
    Includes resolution of the CPSU Central Committee, 1987 July 9.
  - Study, "Major Priorities in Technological Development of US Military Programs,", 1989 April (Box-folder 14: 31)
  - Interview, V. P. Karpov, "Soviets Accept Idea of Arms Inspection," International Herald Tribune, 1989 July 12 (Box-folder 14: 32)
  - KGB information on informal groups in the Soviet Union as of September 22, 1989, printed copy (Box-folder 14: 33)
  - Comments on Radio Free Europe program regarding a new approach of the Soviet Union to the problem of ABM and SDI, 1989 October 13 (Box-folder 14: 34)
  - Analysis, "Comprehensive Anti-missile Shield or a New Twist in the Arms Race Spiral,", 1989 (Box-folder 14: 35)
  - Information on Soviet Scientist Committee for Peace, against Nuclear Threat, 1989 (Box-folder 14: 36)
  - Agreement on cooperation on control of export of commodities and technology between Bulgaria, Hungary, GDR, Poland, Soviet Union, and Czechoslovakia, 1990 September 15 (Box-folder 14: 37)
  - Interview, A. N. IAkovlev, Tribune de l'expansion, Paris, France, 1991 March 29 (Box-folder 14: 38)
  - Analysis, investigation result of the AN-24 airplane catastrophe in Irkutsk, Siberia, 1997 December 6 (Box-folder 14: 39)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 14: 40)
- Electronic Files, 1991-2001 (Box 15)
  Access
  Original disks closed. Use copies of electronic files available in the Hoover Archives reading room.
  Computer disks with working materials from the Cold War period and new technology draft projects.
  The 637 digital files acquired with this collection are primarily in Russian, although some files are in English. A list of the contents of the digital files on each computer disk came with the collection and is provided below, along with a list of the files on each disk. While there is no information linking the descriptive information to specific digital files, the file names may be helpful in identifying the content of the digital files. The descriptions have not been verified by the Hoover Archives, and no other information about the files is available.
  During processing of the original files, most were individually opened by Hoover Archives staff in Microsoft Word as 866 DOS Cyrillic, converted to RTF, and then batch converted to PDF; a prefix of "2002c48_disk0X_" was also added to the PDF file names. A few files were opened in other programs, such as Microsoft Excel, a text editor, or HTML, because they displayed better in those applications, and then saved as PDFs.
  A few files were "edited" by Hoover staff. Editing included replacing corrupted text with characters in cases where one could infer what characters were missing, deleting inefficient page breaks, and deleting corrupted text. These edited files are identified with a "_edited" as a suffix in the file name.
  When using the PDF files on the digital workstation in the Hoover Archives reading room, be sure to always scroll through the entire document, because sometimes there is garbled text at the beginning, but readable text in the middle. Some of the files contain garbled characters that were unrecoverable by the means available to Hoover staff. Several files that were recoverable but could not be saved as PDFs were printed to paper and are available in the boxes of paper documents.
  - Disk01, 2001
    -Composition of Warsaw Pact and NATO in Europe
    -Perestroika in NATO
    -Materials for Baker's trip to Moscow in February 1992
    -Structure of preparing decisions on military-political issues, and the perfection of the structure
    -USSR defense expenditures and their reduction
    -Speech by Lev Zaikov, Politburo member and USSR Defense Council member in charge of the military-industrial complex
    -Newspaper articles
    -Conduct of a briefing on an accident on a Soviet atomic submarine in April 1989
    -Proposals for negotiations with the USA
    -Military-Political Council
    -Defense Council under the USSR president
    -Presidential Council
    -Report on a trip to Cyprus
    -List of documents of the Politburo that went through the Working Group of the Defense Council's "Pyatyorki" in 1990
    -Materials for an interview with Zaikov
    -Approach to counting winged rockets at START negotiation
    -New technology
    -Disagreements in the working group on the text of directives for the delegation to arms talks
    -Negotiations with China on military-political problems
    -Documents for the preparation of sessions of Politburo Commission (Zaikov) -- The Big Five ("Verkhnaya pyatyorka") (42 documents)
    -Materials for Politburo member Ye. K. Ligachev on nationalities relations
    -Proposals of the USA for the number of troops in Europe
    -Declassification of information of special importance regarding Soviet strategic nuclear weapons
    -Documents for Yeltsin's administration
    -Information on the top negotiators
    -Documents for Yu. A. Petrov, leader of Yeltsin's administration (20 documents)
    -Materials for a speech at a CC plenum
    -Theses for Zaikov's speech on military conversion
    -List of documents of the Inter-Departmental Working Group of the "Five" for Military-Political Issues (Politburo resolution)
    -Correspondence of Zaikov with Gorbachev on arms limitations
    -Issues for high-level meetings, 1990 May 30
    -Draft of proposals for the second stage of START negotiations
    -Documents on arms reductions
    -Plan of measures for arms limitations
    -Possible solution to deadlocks in the YaKV negotiations in 1989
    -Materials for a meeting between Obukhov and Baker on 1991 November 25
    -Further reductions under START
    -Directives for the delegation to START talks
    -Concepts for the second stage of the START talks
    -Strategic nuclear arms of England and France
    -Report of Shevardnadze and Zaikov to Gorbachev
    -Report of the Zaikov Commission to Gorbachev
    -Showing the American side USSR nuclear warheads
    -Codes of NATO for Soviet rockets
    -Quantity of nuclear material
    -Transport of hard fuel engines
    -Interconnection of the START and ABM negotiations
    -Comparison of arms and military technology of the Warsaw Pact and NATO (20 tables)
    -Redeployment of armaments behind the Urals
    -Issues regarding exchange of data on conventional arms in Europe
    -Number of personnel of the armed forces of the countries of the Warsaw Pact and NATO
    -Geographic zone of negotiations at Vienna meeting
    -Concept for European security
    -Materials for a conference on disarmament
    -Correlation of forces in Central Europe after reductions
    -Materials for CFE talks
    -Re-basing of American F-16s from Spain to Italy
    -Joint statement of the SEPG and the Social Democratic Party of Germany
    -Zaikov to Yazov on the Vienna talks
    -Materials of a meeting with Zaikov
    -Disagreements between departments regarding issues of arms in Europe
    -Materials on the WTO-NATO for Gorbachev's meeting with Baker, 1989 May 11
    -Concept of "Open Skies"
    -Report to Gorbachev on conventional arms
    -Discussion of proposals by the USA on closed areas
    -WTO and NATO quantities in Europe
    -Comparison of attack aviation of the WTO and NATO
    -Problems regarding withdrawal of USSR troops from the WTO states
    -Condition of armed forces in the USSR and USA
    -Expenditures on military-technical cooperation
    -USSR military budget compared to USA, and expenses on space
    -Space weapons
    -USSR's position on problems of non-proliferation of rocket technology
    -Problems of VPK conversion
    -Global laboratory for nuclear security
    -Correspondence of Zaikov with Shevardnadze on anti-satellite systems
    -Comments of O. D. Baklanov, CC secretary for the VPK and Defense and Security Councils member, on the draft decision of the Defense Council
    -Throw-weight of delivery vehicles
    -Soviet-American consultations regarding issues of nuclear non-proliferation
    -Ending nuclear testing
    -Problems of the nuclear arsenal in Europe
    -Rocket "Oka" on WTO troops
    -Consequences of concluding a Soviet-American INF treaty (outline for the CPSU CC leadership)
    -Comparison of US and USSR intercontinental ballistic missiles
    -Materials on the "VITA" project rendering emergency assistance
    -Television interview about the main construction engineer of the "Yuzhnoe" plant, M. K. Yangel
    -Soviet-American consultations ont he banning of chemical weapons
    -Charges against the USSR on proliferating chemical weapons
    -Materials for meetings with specialists in the VPK
    - 2-08.TXT
    - ARGUMENT.TXT
    - ARM-USA.TXT
    - ARM-USSR.TXT
    - AUSTRALI.TXT
    - AXPOMEEB.TXT
    - BAKLA-07.TXT
    - BAKLA-B.TXT
    - BALTIC.TXT
    - BC-1.TXT
    - BC-COOTN.TXT
    - BC-PACX.TXT
    - BC.TXT
    - BCTP2511.TXT
    - BEC-MBR.TXT
    - BEHA-ZON.TXT
    - BEHA.TXT
    - BELJAK-1.TXT
    - BELJAK-2.TXT
    - BELJAK-3.TXT
    - BRIDGE.TXT
    - BRIFING.TXT
    - BTC-BAKL.TXT
    - BTC-PACX.TXT
    - BTOPOI-A.TXT
    - BTOPOI-B.TXT
    - BTOPOI-F.TXT
    - BTOROI.TXT
    - BUDG-SSR.TXT
    - BUDG-US.TXT
    - CENTR-EV.TXT
    - CHARGE.TXT
    - CHB-1989.TXT
    - CHB-1990.TXT
    - CHB-1997.TXT
    - CHB-2005.TXT
    - CHB-USA.TXT
    - COBET-1.TXT
    - COBET-2.TXT
    - COBET-6.TXT
    - COBET-O.TXT
    - COBET-PR.TXT
    - COBET.TXT
    - COCTAB.TXT
    - COKPA.TXT
    - CONCEPT.TXT
    - CONTROL.TXT
    - COSMOS.TXT
    - CYPRUS.TXT
    - DIREC-19.TXT
    - DIREC.TXT
    - DIRECTIV.TXT
    - DOC.TXT
    - DOKUM-90.TXT
    - DOKUM-91.TXT
    - EUR-35.TXT
    - EUR-DOG.TXT
    - EURO-23.TXT
    - EURO-BEZ.TXT
    - F-16.TXT
    - FRA-ANG.TXT
    - GDR-FRG.TXT
    - GOROHOV.TXT
    - GRUPPA-1.TXT
    - GRUPPA-2.TXT
    - GRUPPA-3.TXT
    - GRUPPA-4.TXT
    - GRUPPA.TXT
    - HATO-OBD.TXT
    - HJUSTON.TXT
    - INTERV.TXT
    - IS-M.TXT
    - JANGEL.TXT
    - JAZOV.TXT
    - KAT-MATR.TXT
    - KOHBEPC.TXT
    - KOMISS2.TXT
    - KOMISSIA.TXT
    - KP-AXPOM.TXT
    - KP-DOKL.TXT
    - KP-HAKO.TXT
    - KP-HATO.TXT
    - KP-NAVU.TXT
    - KRVB-1.TXT
    - LABORAT.TXT
    - LEV-MSG.TXT
    - LEV-MSG2.TXT
    - LEW-1.TXT
    - LEW-10.TXT
    - LEW-11.TXT
    - LEW-12.TXT
    - LEW-13.TXT
    - LEW-14.TXT
    - LEW-16.TXT
    - LEW-2.TXT
    - LEW-28.TXT
    - LEW-3.TXT
    - LEW-4.TXT
    - LEW-5.TXT
    - LEW-6.TXT
    - LEW-7.TXT
    - LEW-8.TXT
    - LEW-9.TXT
    - LEW-A.TXT
    - LEW-B.TXT
    - LEW-BEHA.TXT
    - LEW-C.TXT
    - LEW-D.TXT
    - LEW-E.TXT
    - LEW-F.TXT
    - LEW-G.TXT
    - LEW-H.TXT
    - LEW-IS.TXT
    - LEW-JAZ.TXT
    - LEW-L.TXT
    - LEW-O.TXT
    - LEW-P.TXT
    - LEW-R.TXT
    - LEW-S-1.TXT
    - LEW-S-2.TXT
    - LEW-S.TXT
    - LEW-T.TXT
    - LEW-U-1.TXT
    - LEW-X.TXT
    - LEW-Y.TXT
    - LEW-Z-1.TXT
    - LEW-Z.TXT
    - LIGATHEV.TXT
    - MIHAILO.TXT
    - MIHAILO1.TXT
    - MITING.TXT
    - MSG-2.TXT
    - MSG-30.TXT
    - MSG-3005.TXT
    - MSG-30A.TXT
    - MSG-30B.TXT
    - MSG-BTOP.TXT
    - MSG-FIN.TXT
    - MSG-VEL.TXT
    - MSG.TXT
    - NATIONAL.TXT
    - NATO.TXT
    - ODWTCCCP.TXT
    - OFFERS.TXT
    - OGEREL-1.TXT
    - OPEN-SCY.TXT
    - OTDEL-2.TXT
    - OTDEL-3.TXT
    - OTDEL-9.TXT
    - OTTAVA.TXT
    - OTVET.TXT
    - OWD.TXT
    - PACCEKP1.TXT
    - PACCEKP2.TXT
    - PACX-KOC.TXT
    - PEREG.TXT
    - PETROV-1.TXT
    - PETROV-2.TXT
    - PETROV-3.TXT
    - PETROV-4.TXT
    - PETROV-5.TXT
    - PETROV-6.TXT
    - PETROV-7.TXT
    - PETROV-8.TXT
    - PETROV-9.TXT
    - PETROV-A.TXT
    - PETROV-B.TXT
    - PETROV-C.TXT
    - PETROV-D.TXT
    - PETROV-E.TXT
    - PETROV-F.TXT
    - PETROV-G.TXT
    - PETROV-H.TXT
    - PETROV-I.TXT
    - PETROV-U.TXT
    - PLAN.TXT
    - PLATFORM.TXT
    - PLENUM-1.TXT
    - PLENUM.TXT
    - POST-356.TXT
    - PRACTIC.TXT
    - PREZ-18.TXT
    - PREZ-19.TXT
    - PREZ-OC.TXT
    - PREZ-OCB.TXT
    - PREZ-SU.TXT
    - PU-PL.TXT
    - RAJON.TXT
    - RATIFIC.TXT
    - SKOKOV.TXT
    - SPISOK.TXT
    - SRAWN-1.TXT
    - SRAWN-2.TXT
    - SRAWN-3.TXT
    - SRAWN-4.TXT
    - SRAWN-5.TXT
    - SRAWN-6.TXT
    - SRAWN-7.TXT
    - SRAWN-8.TXT
    - SS-18INS.TXT
    - SS-N-18.TXT
    - STATSIC.TXT
    - TAKE-OUT.TXT
    - TEZIS.TXT
    - UFA.TXT
    - UNSPREAD.TXT
    - US-USSR.TXT
    - UTKIN.TXT
    - VITA-1.TXT
    - VITA-2.TXT
    - VITA-3.TXT
    - VITA-4.TXT
    - VITA-5.TXT
    - VITA-6.TXT
    - VITA-7.TXT
    - VITA-8.TXT
    - VITA-9.TXT
    - VITA1.TXT
    - WOPROS.TXT
    - XIM-CONS.TXT
    - XIM-LIKV.TXT
    - XIM-TOLK.TXT
    - XIM.TXT
    - ZA-URAL.TXT
  - Disk02, 1991-2001; Bulk, 2001
    -Orders of the CPSU CC secretaries
    -List of documents of the Politburo that passed through the Inter-Departmental Working Group on the VPK in 1990
    -Winged rockets of NATO, the USA, and USSR
    -Approaches to counting winged rockets in negotiations
    -List of issues for review at a high level meeting on 1990 May 30; materials for the meeting
    -Proposals for the second stage of START talks
    -On the letter of academician Ye. V. Velikhov on issues of halting nuclear testing
    -List of orders on START limitations
    -Plan of work of USSR departments dealing with arms limitations
    -List of issues regarding Soviet-American negotiations--recommendations of the "pyatyorki" for the USSR mass media
    -USA's "Tomahawk"
    -Structure for the control of weapons in the USSR up to 1985 and from 1986 to 1991
    -Deployment of weapons and military technology in Afghanistan
    -Deployment of military technology in WTO countries
    -USSR expenditures on military-technical cooperation
    -Showing military technology to representatives of the USA
    -Newspaper articles on START and SDI
    -Issues in German reunification
    -Rendering technical assistance to India in the construction of the atomic submarine "S-2"
    -Military-technical cooperation with Iran
    -Presence of planes in Cuba
    -Plans for military-technical cooperation
    -Theses for a speech by Politburo member Zaikov on USSR military doctrine and START limitations
    -Working materials on military aspects of security
    -Creation of a Center for Comprehensive Research
    -Materials from various press articles on problems on strategic nuclear forces and the VPK
    -Graph of the structure for working out issues and the preparation of decisions regarding military-political issues in the USSR at the end of the 1980s
    -Memo to Zaikov
    -Materials for negotiations with the USA
    -Foreign economic ties of Russia during VPK conversion
    -Report on personal activity in the "Yuzhnoe" plant and the Inter-Departmental Working Group ("pyatyorke")
    -Articles on problems regarding NATO
    -Articles on SDI
    -Articles on strategic nuclear arms
    -Materials for START talks
    -Quantity of strategic nuclear arms in 1990
    -Opinion of a specialist on the danger of the use of the heavy rocket SS-18 in rendering operation assistance
    -Assigned procurement of arms and military technology in 1992
    -Issues of the utilization of weapons
    -Report on VPK conversion in the USSR
    -Materials for a grant on the problem of aerodynamic of space vehicles in space systems
    -Letter to Russia's representative in Brussels, I. S. Silaev, regarding creation of a European space system
    -Space System Concept (in English)
    -Correspondence with the government regarding space systems